Buckley vs. Vidal. 2 Men. 10 Debates. Television Would Never Be the Same.
Best of Enemies is a documentary, history film directed by Morgan Neville.
A documentary about the legendary series of nationally televised debates in 1968 between two
great public intellectuals, the liberal Gore Vidal and the conservative William F.
Buckley Jr.
Intended as commentary on the issues of their day, these vitriolic and explosive encounters came to define the modern era of public discourse in the
media, marking the big bang moment of our contemporary media landscape when spectacle trumped content and argument replaced substance.
Best of Enemies delves into the entangled biographies of these two great thinkers, and luxuriates in the language and the theater of
their debates, begging the question, "What has television done to the way we discuss politics in our democracy today?"
Self, played by Gore Vidal.
Self, played by William F. Buckley Jr..
Voice of William F. Buckley, played by Kelsey Grammer.
Voice of Gore Vidal, played by John Lithgow.
Self, played by Dick Cavett.
Self, played by Christopher Hitchens.
Best of Enemies is a 2015 American documentary film co-directed by Robert Gordon and Morgan
Neville about the televised debates between intellectuals Gore Vidal and William F.
Buckley Jr.
during the 1968 United States presidential election.
The film premiered at the 2015 Sundance Film Festival.
It was acquired by Magnolia and Participant Media.
The film took five years to make because of struggles to secure
funding, get interviews, and uncover archival footage.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, miami,
florida, politics, intellectual, author.
The tone is thought_provoking.